Joomart Achekeev

joomart.achekeev@gmail.com | (609) 455-3245 | Plainsboro, New Jersey | linkedin.com/in/joomart-achekeev/ | github.com/jomadata | jomadata.github.io

Skills

Data mining, Data cleaning, Data processing, Data engineering, Tableau, Python, Java, Pandas, NumPy, Scikit-learn, Matplotlib, Seaborn, NLTK, Tensorflow/Keras, SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Linux/Windows/MacOS, MS Office.

Profile

Experienced and driven Data Scientist/Analyst, constantly delivering measurable results, with 5+ years in data analytics, and a strong background in programming. Certified in Tableau Desktop and project management. Expert in simplifying complex challenges to drive data-driven decision-making. Dedicated to continuous professional development. Experienced in working autonomously and within collaborative teams of up to 5 people.

Experience

Data Analyst, Oct 2022 - Present

Lingraphica, United States

- Played a key participation role in achieving a consistent year-over-year increase of 19% in sales since joining the company.
- Identified a key data error, that when fixed, improved the data quality by 20%
- Initiated and implemented 2 projects in my first year to disseminate data analytic products to the company employees.
- Develop reports based on 3 tier approach: high-level aggregate, mid-level intermediate, and low-level individual analytics.

Online Data Science Immersive Fellow, Oct 2021 – Jan 2022

General Assembly, United States

- Completed 3 individual and 2 team data science projects in linear regression modeling, web scraping, NLP, decision trees, and stacking techniques.
- Trained machine learning models with up to 95% accuracy on Ames housing, Reddit, population, unemployment, and Yelp academic datasets.
- Achieved 100% completion of all project requirements within set timelines.

Backend web developer, Sep 2017 – Jul 2021

Yorc

- Designed and configured databases and developed backend support for 30+ web applications.
- Ensured the team met project requirements, achieving a 95% client satisfaction rate and 90% deadline compliance.

Junior Backend web developer, Aug 2016 – Aug 2017

Put In Byte

- Constructed backend apps and databases for 6+ projects.
- Reviewed Python code to troubleshoot and improve the performance of 10+ projects.

Backend web development intern, Apr 2016 – Jul 2016

Put In Byte

- Produced Django templates for the backend framework in 3 projects.
- Wrote 4 multiprocessing web scrapers using BeautifulSoup and Requests libraries.

Research Project Manager, Nov 2013 – Mar 2016

M-Vector Research and Consulting

- Successfully ran 50+ research projects with all outcomes delivered on time and within an agreed budget.
- Achieved a total research project cost of \$2 million.

Research Analyst, Feb 2011 – Oct 2013

M-Vector Research and Consulting

- Devised and executed efficient data collection methods and instruments for 35+ projects with a 95% initial acceptance rate.
- Improved client satisfaction by introducing multilingual background data search, by 10%.

Education

OSCE Academy

Master of Arts in Economics (Diploma in Economic Governance and Development)

American University in Central Asia

Bachelor of Arts in Business Administration (Diploma in Marketing and Management)

Certification

Tableau Desktop Specialist Certificate – Tableau Software Services

Data Science Immersive - General Assembly

Project Management Level-C Certificate - International Project Management Association (#LATV-C0155)